As we covered in the previous video,
there are quite a lot of formatting
tools that you can use within Excel
to enhance the meaning and appearance
of your document and your data.
Another useful tool is
the page layout tool.
And if we go up to the page
layout, there are a range of
features that we can utilise here.
So one of the things there is, if I
decided to go to print this document at
the moment and selected print, as you can
see that is showing on more than one page.
So if I wanted to print it, it
would automatically print on two
page, which wouldn't be appropriate.
You would then have to put
the two pages together.
I can change the orientation to landscape.
And as you can see, this would still
be displayed on two pages because if
you can see this dotted line going down
between column J and K, that is pretty
much means that that is the page break.
Now you can see the page break, if you go
down to the bottom right-hand corner and
you look at the three options there: page
break, preview page layout, and normal.
So if I go to page break, you can see
that that is where the page break will be.
So page two will be there, but I can
actually move the page break along.
So that would all be on page one.
Now that will resize that to make
sure that it'll all fit on one page.
So if I go back to normal view and then
go to print, as you can see, all of
the information is now visible on one
page, which is suitable for printing.
You always want to make sure that you
don't break data up on multiple pages.
So even if you have an awful lot of
information, you can still reduce the
size so that it will fit on one page
by going to the custom scaling option.
And if I went to custom scaling and I
selected fit all columns on one page,
that would shrink the information down
so that everything would fit on a page.
It will reduce the size,
obviously things will get smaller.
If I had, for example, 30 or 40
columns to be shown and selected fit
all columns on one page, obviously it
would have to resize them and reduce
the size to ensure that they all fit.
So I can just go back to that.
And as we covered the tables formatting
in the previous video, what I'm going
to look at here is the actual themes.
So themes are very similar to the
themes that you had in PowerPoint
where you could apply the office theme,
the facet theme, gallery, integral.
So there was quite a lot, and these pretty
much mirror exactly the sort of themes.
It's the colour scheme
that's being mirrored.
So you had, Basis, Berlin, Circuit.
So you have quite a lot of different
themes that you could choose from.
And if I just select one of
those for now, as you can see
that has applied that theme.
But again, it has stretched
that over, on to page two.
You can always tell the page
because of this dotted line.
And one of the things that, again, I'll
go back to that and I'll just change
the page, so that disappears so we've
still got one page, but one of the
other things to be aware of is that.
When you set your print area, if you just
want to print everything, that's fine.
So it would just print that.
But if you only needed to print, perhaps
that information there, or even just
so we'll just check all of the, the
monthly sales and we set the print area.
So if I click set print area,
now and then went to print.
As you can see, it is only going to print
that information that I have selected.
So you've got your margins as well.
You can change the margins of the page.
You can have a change the the size of the
paper and the print area, the background.
Again, you can apply a background to that.
So you could apply a coloured background or
a picture to be shown in the background.
You don't normally do that, but
it is something that you can do.
And again, some of these, you can have
a look up, you can see the grid lines
or you can take the grid lines off.
You can see the headings or
you can take the headings off.
So you can align everything to the left
center, right align, but that would be,
I would need to select all the data and
it, because I have a theme set I can't
actually use that tool at the moment.
So as you can see, it's all greyed out.
If I can't, if it's grayed out, that
means I can't actually use that.
So you can have a look around
in here and see if any of the
various tools that you wish to use.
There's various effects that can be used.
colour themes that can be used.
And again, this is all just to enhance
the meaning and appearance of the
document for when you're printing
it or presenting it to an audience.